Guide to the Herbert Feigl Papers, 1916-1973 ASP.1997.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence, 1923-1973; III.
  - Personal and Professional, 1923-1973; 1.
    - McClure, George, 1966 (Folder 67)
    - McConnell, R. A., 1952-1971 (Folder 68)
    - McConnell, T. R., 1943-1949 (Folder 69)
    - McCredie, H., 1972 (Folder 70)
    - McDiarmid, E. W., 1950-1961 (Folder 71)
    - McGuigan, F. J., 1955 (Folder 72)
    - Machlup, Fritz, 1959 (Folder 73)
    - McKaughlin, Robert, 1966 (Folder 74)
    - McLaughlin, Andrew, 1970 (Folder 75)
    - McLaughlin, Michael, 1964 (Folder 76)
    - McLaughlin, Robert M., 1966 (Folder 77)
    - McMullin, Ernan, 1964-1966 (Folder 78)
    - Magee, W. T., Rt. Rev. Msgr., 1966 (Folder 79)
    - Magel, Charles, 1962 (Folder 80)
    - Magrish, James L., 1954 (Folder 81)
    - Malcolm, Norman, 1958 (Folder 82)
    - Mandler, George, 1955 (Folder 83)
    - Margenau, Henry, 1954 (Folder 84)
    - Marrow, Alfred J., 1967 (Folder 85)
    - Marsh, H. Clifton, 1970 (Folder 86)
    - Martin, Herbert, 1931, 1940 (Folder 87)
    - Martin, Norman M., 1960 (Folder 88)
    - Martin, Richard M., 1954 (Folder 89)
    - Massey, Gerald J., 1967 (Folder 90)
    - Matross, Gerald, 1965 (Folder 91)
    - Maxwell, Grover, 1954-1967 (Folder 92)
    - Maynez, Eduardo Garcia, 1964 (Folder 93)
    - Meehl, Paul E., 1951-1971 (Folder 94)
    - Mellor, Hugh, 1967 (Folder 95)
    - Menger, Karl, 1959 (Folder 96)
    - Menninger, Karl A., 1936, 1955 (Folder 97)
    - Metz, André, 1955 (Folder 98)
    - Meyer, Hans, 1929 (Folder 99)
    - Miller, Cecil, 1965-1967 (Folder 100)
    - Miller, David C., 1959-1960 (Folder 101)
    - Miller, Dickinson S., 1927-1950 (Folder 102)
    - Miller, Neal E., 1954 (Reel 5 & 5a, Folder 103)
    - Miller, Paul R., 1959 (Folder 104)
    - Moe, Henry Allen, 1947 (Folder 105)
    - Moore, Charles A., 1958-1962 (Folder 106)
    - Morgenbesser, Sidney, 1961-1966 (Folder 107)
    - Morrill, J. L., 1947-1961 (Folder 108)
    - Morris, Charles W., 1937-1971 (Folder 109)
    - Mosher, William W., 1955 (Folder 110)
    - Mulder, H. L., 1964 (Folder 111)
    - Myers, Francis, 1949-1965 (Folder 112)
    - Nagel, Ernest, 1943-1971 (Folder 113)
    - Nagley, Winfield E., 1960-1970 (Folder 114)
    - Nash, Harvey, 1958 (Folder 115)
    - Nelson, Everett J., 1966-1967 (Folder 116)
    - Neumann, Sigmund, 1961 (Folder 117)
    - Neurath, Otto, 1934-1944 (Folder 118)
    - Nevarskar, Balwant, 1958 (Folder 119)
    - Nieuwejaar, Claus E. (Folder 120)
    - Nolte, J. M., 1946 (Folder 121)
    - Norton, David, 1965-1967 (Folder 122)
    - Noxon, James, 1964 (Folder 123)
    - Nygren, Anders, 1961 (Folder 124)
    - Oates, Whitney J., 1959 (Folder 125)
    - O'Neil, William M., 1958-1963 (Folder 126)
    - Oppacher, Franz, 1968 (Folder 127)
    - Oppenheim, Felix, 1965 (Folder 128)
    - Oppenheim, Paul, 1954-1968 (Folder 129)
    - Orenstein, Ernst, 1959 (Folder 130)
    - Ostensoe, James G., 1960 (Folder 131)
    - Otero, Mario H., 1965-1966 (Folder 132)
    - Otto, Max, 1964 (Folder 133)
    - Pap, Arthur, 1928-1959 (Folder 134)
    - Parker, Ernest L., 1957, 1961 (Folder 135)
    - Pasch, Alan, 1966-1967 (Folder 136)
    - Pasquinelli, Alberto, 1959 (Folder 137)
    - Passmore, John A., 1964-1965 (Folder 138)
    - Patch, Frances G., 1964 (Folder 139)
    - Patrick, G. T. W., 1931, 1935 (Folder 140)
    - Pawlowski, Tadeusz, 1960 (Folder 141)
    - Peake, Charles H., 1960 (Folder 142)
    - Peckham, Morse, 1953-1954 (Folder 143)
    - Pepper, Stephen C., 1954-1970 (Folder 144)
    - Peterson, Webster J., 1962 (Folder 145)
    - Phillips, Lakin, 1953 (Folder 146)
    - Phillips, Mary, 1966 (Folder 147)
    - Piccone, Paul, 1965 (Folder 148)
    - Pilgrim, Robert, 1967 (Folder 149)
    - Pitcher, George, 1962 (Folder 150)
    - Plank, Clifford, 1967 (Folder 151)
    - Platt, John R., 1960 (Folder 152)
    - Polanyi, Michael, 1960, 1969 (Folder 153)
    - Politis, C., 1963-1964 (Folder 154)
    - Pollak, John C., 1970 (Folder 155)
    - Popper, Karl R., 1959-1969 (Folder 156)
    - Poter, B. (Folder 157)
    - Posnanski, Edward, 1956 (Folder 158)
    - Pratt, Carroll C., 1940, 1945 (Folder 159)
    - Price H. H., 1959 (Folder 160)
    - Pulley, William, 1966 (Folder 161)
    - Pumpian-Mindlin, E., 1960 (Folder 162)
    - Pusey, Nathan M., 1964 (Folder 163)
    - Putnam, Hilary, 1956 (Folder 164)
    - Quine, W. V. O., 1961-1966 (Folder 165)
    - Raab, Francis, 1960 (Folder 166)
    - Raju, P. T., 1962 (Folder 167)
    - Ramsey, O. Bertrand, 1966 (Folder 168)
    - Ramsperger, Albert, 1945, 1950 (Folder 169)
    - Rapaport, David, 1958 (Folder 170)
    - Reese, George, 1959 (Folder 171)
    - Reichenbach, Hans, 1927-1953 (Folder 172)
    - Reichenbach, Maria, 1957-1970 (Folder 173)
    - Rescher, Nicholas, 1954-1967 (Folder 174)
    - Rie, Robert, 1961 (Folder 175)
    - Rindaner, Gerhart, 1961 (Folder 176)
    - Ritchie, Benbow F., 1953-1954 (Folder 177)
    - Robinson, Edward Schouten, 1955-1966 (Folder 178)
    - Rogers, Donald P., 1959 (Folder 179)
    - Rollins, Calvin D., 1961-1965 (Folder 180)
    - Rose, Lynn E., 1965-1966 (Folder 181)
    - Rosenblith, Walter A., 1959 (Folder 182)
    - Rosenzweig, Mark R., 1955 (Folder 183)
    - Rossi, Alejandro, 1971 (Folder 184)
    - Rothstein, Jerome, 1951-1952 (Folder 185)
    - Rotta, H., 1959-1960 (Folder 186)
    - Rotter, Elfriede, 1961 (Folder 187)
    - Royce, Joseph R., 1964 (Folder 188)
    - Rozeboom, William W., 1955-1971 (Folder 189)
    - Rubenstein, Ben O., 1958 (Folder 190)
    - Rudner, Richard, 1953-1962 (Folder 191)
    - Russell, Bertrand (Folder 192)
    - Ruytinx, Jacques (Folder 193)
    - Ryle, Gilbert, 1954 (Folder 194)
    - Rynin, David, 1944-1970 (Folder 195)
    - Sagoroff, S., 1964 (Folder 196)
    - Sakamoto, Hyakudai, 1957 (Folder 197)
    - Salmon, Wesley C., 1955-1966 (Folder 198)
    - Sandin, R. B., 1964 (Folder 199)
    - Sankaran, S., 1964 (Folder 200)
    - Savage, T. R., 1962 (Folder 201)
    - Savery, Barnett, 1961 (Folder 202)
    - Sawyer, Philip, 1965 (Folder 203)
    - Sayre, Kenneth M., 1966 (Folder 204)
    - Schaffner, Kenneth F., 1969-1970 (Folder 205)
    - Scher, Jordan M., 1959-1962 (Folder 206)
    - Scherer, Donald, 1970 (Folder 207)
    - Schilpp, Paul A., 1953-1971 (Folder 208)
    - Schlegel, Richard, 1956-1967 (Folder 209)
    - Schlesinger, Edmond R., 1964 (Folder 210)
    - Schelsinger, George, 1964-1967 (Folder 211)
    - Schmidt, Paul F., 1961 (Folder 212)
    - Scholz, Heinrich, 1950 (Folder 213)
    - Schwyzer, Hubert R. G., 1959 (Folder 214)
    - Scriven, Michael, 1957-1965 (Folder 215)
    - Seaman, Francis, 1967 (Folder 216)
    - Seashore, C. E., 1933 (Folder 217)
    - Seeley, John R., 1966 (Folder 218)
    - Seeman, William, 1955 (Folder 219)
    - Segy, Ladislas, 1966 (Folder 220)
    - Sellars, Roy W., 1945, 1966 (Folder 221)
    - Sellars, Wilfrid, 1945-1966 (Folder 222)
    - Settle, Thomas W., 1965-1968 (Folder 223)
    - Shalya, Yash D., 1962 (Folder 224)
    - Sharma, Ved, 1962 (Folder 225)
    - Shaw, Daniel, 1965 (Folder 226)
    - Sheehan, Robert, 1966 (Folder 227)
    - Shimony, Abner, 1958-1969 (Folder 228)
    - Shute, Clarence, 1957 (Folder 229)
    - Shwayder, David S., 1953 (Folder 230)
    - Sibley, Mulford, 1969 (Folder 231)
    - Siekert, Robert G., 1969 (Folder 232)
    - Sills, David L., 1964 (Folder 233)
    - Simon, Walter B., 1961 (Folder 234)
    - Sinclair, Gregg, M., 1959 (Folder 235)
    - Skinner, B. F., 1957-1970 (Folder 236)
    - Smart, J. J. C., 1958-1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Smith, John E., 1962-1966 (Folder 2)
    - Smullyan, Arthur, 1961 (Folder 3)
    - Smollner, Karl, 1960 (Folder 4)
    - Somerville, John, 1961 (Folder 5)
    - Sontag, Frederick, 1961 (Folder 6)
    - Sosensky, Irving, 1965-1966 (Folder 7)
    - Spector, Marshall, 1962 (Folder 8)
    - Spence, Kenneth W., 1953-1954 (Folder 9)
    - Stace, Walter (Folder 10)
    - Stanford, E. B., 1958, 1962 (Folder 11)
    - Stannard, J., 1958 (Folder 12)
    - Starkey, Lawrence H., 1970 (Folder 13)
    - Stearns, Barbara, 1963 (Folder 14)
    - Stegmüller, Wolfgang, 1959-1970 (Folder 15)
    - Steinkraus, W. E., 1965 (Folder 16)
    - Stevenson, C. L., 1945 (Folder 17)
    - Stewart, Daniel K., 1964 (Folder 18)
    - Stewart, G. W., 1939-1940 (Folder 19)
    - Stocker, Michael A. G., 1964 (Folder 20)
    - Stoddard, George D., 1935, 1940 (Folder 21)
    - Stout, Alan K., 1966 (Folder 22)
    - Stove, David, 1964 (Folder 23)
    - Strawson, P. F., 1955 (Folder 24)
    - Streeter, John W., 1959 (Folder 25)
    - Stuewer, Roger H., 1967-1968 (Folder 26)
    - Suchting, W. A., 1965, 1971 (Folder 27)
    - Swenson, David F., 1934 (Folder 28)
    - Szkarlatovska, Irene, 1963 (Folder 29)
    - Szorenyi-Reischl, N. A., 1965 (Folder 30)
    - Tai Tsun Wu, 1951 (Folder 31)
    - Tapp, Robert B., 1966 (Folder 32)
    - Tate, John T., 1940 (Folder 33)
    - Taubes, Jacob, 1966 (Folder 34)
    - Terrell, D. Burnham, 1964 (Folder 35)
    - Thalberg, Irving, 1965 (Folder 36)
    - Thayer, H. S., 1952 (Folder 37)
    - Thistlewaite, Donald L., 1954 (Folder 38)
    - Thompson, Norma S., 1940 (Folder 39)
    - Thygeson, Phillips, 1953 (Folder 40)
    - Tierney, R. Joel, 1966 (Folder 41)
    - Tintner, Gerhard, 1970 (Folder 42)
    - Tisdale, W. E., 1931 (Folder 43)
    - Tolman, Edward C., 1946 (Folder 44)
    - Tolman, Edward C. (Folder 45)
    - Tomas, Vincent, 1958 (Folder 46)
    - Toulmin, Stephen, 1959, 1966 (Folder 47)
    - Treloar, Alan E., 1958 (Folder 48)
    - Turnbull, John, 1966-1970 (Folder 49)
    - Turnbull, Murray, 1960 (Folder 50)
    - Turnbull, Robert G., 1955 (Folder 51)
    - Turner, Joseph, 1953 (Folder 52)
    - Tyler, Ralph W., 1960 (Folder 53)
    - Vaihinger, Hans, 1923, 1929 (Folder 54)
    - van de Velde, Barbara, 1969 (Folder 55)
    - van Praag, J. P., 1966 (Folder 56)
    - Veatih, Henry, 1961 (Folder 57)
    - Victor, Laurence J., 1964 (Folder 58)
    - Visscher, Maurice B., 1949-1961 (Folder 59)
    - Vivas, Eliseo, 1966 (Folder 60)
    - Vlastos, Gregory, 1962 (Folder 61)
    - von Hayek, F. A., 1954 (Folder 62)
    - von Wright, Georg H., 1971 (Folder 63)
    - Waelder, Robert, 1962 (Folder 64)
    - Waggoner, George R., 1960 (Folder 65)
    - Walker, Charles U., 1966 (Folder 66)
    - Wallis, Wilson D., 1955 (Folder 67)
    - Wallraff, Charles F., 1958 (Folder 68)
    - Wangensteen, Owen H., 1955 (Folder 69)
    - Ward, J. N., 1967 (Folder 70)
    - Warnken, E. Lorraine, 1966 (Folder 71)
    - Warren, Phillip W., 1966 (Folder 72)
    - Wartofsky, Marx W., 1961 (Folder 73)
    - Wasser, Henry, 1960 (Folder 74)
    - Watanabe, Michael S., 1967 (Folder 75)
    - Weeden, William J., 1965 (Folder 76)
    - Weinberg, Julius, 1966 (Folder 77)
    - Weiner, Charles, 1966-1967 (Folder 78)
    - Weingartner, Paul, 1961, 1964 (Folder 79)
    - Weiss, Hans, 1958 (Folder 80)
    - Weiss, Isi, 1952 (Folder 81)
    - Weiss, Wilhelm, 1949 (Folder 82)
    - Weizsaecker, C. F. von, 1957 (Folder 83)
    - Wender, Paul H., 1960 (Folder 84)
    - Werkmeister, W. H., 1945, 1962 (Folder 85)
    - Whitehead, Alfred North, 1931 (Folder 86)
    - Whyte, L. L., 1955 (Folder 87)
    - Wick, Warner, 1956 (Folder 88)
    - Wieck, David, 1967 (Folder 89)
    - Wier, Roy W., 1960 (Folder 90)
    - Will, Frederick, L., 1959 (Folder 91)
    - Williams, Donald C., 1934-1956 (Folder 92)
    - Wilson, O. Meredith, 1961-1966 (Folder 93)
    - Winn, Ralph B., 1954 (Folder 94)
    - Wisdom, John O., 1955 (Folder 95)
    - Witte, Wilhelm, 1961 (Folder 96)
    - Wold, Herman, 1958 (Folder 97)
    - Wolman, Benjamin B., 1961-1962 (Folder 98)
    - Woodger, J. H., 1970 (Folder 99)
    - Woodruff, Arthur E., 1960 (Folder 100)
    - Woodruff, Peter W., 1966 (Folder 101)
    - Wooleyhan, Alfred M., 1939 (Folder 102)
    - Wright, A. Gilbert, 1960 (Folder 103)
    - Wright, Harold, 1959 (Folder 104)
    - Wünzinzer, Karl F., 1935 (Folder 105)
    - Yolton, John W., 1965 (Folder 106)
    - Yourgrau, W., 1964 (Folder 107)
    - Yuen, H. K., 1962 (Folder 108)
    - Zapiain, Luis Aldama, 1963 (Folder 109)
    - Zeisel, Hans, 1961-1971 (Folder 110)
    - Zener, Karl, 1954 (Folder 111)
    - Ziebarth, E. W., 1963-1966 (Folder 112)
    - Ziegler, Howard J. B., 1954 (Folder 113)
    - Zien, Shane, 1953 (Folder 114)
    - Zilsel, E., 1934 (Folder 115)
    - Zweig, Arnulf, 1954 (Folder 116)
    - Miscellaneous personal and professional, 1956-1966 (Folder 117)
    - (Unidentified), 1950-1973 (Folder 118)
    - Lecture Invitations and Acknowledgements, 1938-1970 (Reel 6, Folder 119)
    - Permissions, 1954-1970 (Folder 120)
    - Postcards (unused or unidentified) (Folder 121)
    - Recommendations, 1950-1966 (Folder 122)
    - Requests for Reprints, etc., 1949-1971 (Folder 123)
  - Organizations and Publishers, 1929-1972; 2.
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1955 (Folder 124)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1961 (Folder 125)
    - American Ethical Union, 1966-67 (Folder 126)
    - American Foundations Information Service, 1959 (Folder 127)
    - American Humanist Association, 1944-1965 (Folder 128)
    - American Psychological Association, 1958 (Folder 129)
    - Asia Foundation, 1960, 1962 (Folder 130)
    - Institute of International Education, 1962 (Folder 131)
    - Addison-Wesley, 1967 (Folder 132)
    - Appleton-Century-Crofts, 1953-1968 (Folder 133)
    - Bobbs-Merrill, 1964 (Folder 134)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons -- Dictionary of the History of Ideas, 1967-1971 (Folder 135)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons -- Dictionary of Scientific Biography, 1968 (Folder 136)
    - Collier Books, 1961 (Folder 137)
    - Dover, 1953-1962 (Folder 138)
    - Encyclopedia Americana, 1961 (Folder 139)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1970-1971 (Folder 140)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica -- Great Ideas Today, 1967-1969 (Folder 141)
    - Free Press, 1961 (Folder 142)
    - Grolier Society, 1960 (Folder 143)
    - Harper & Row, 1963-1964 (Folder 144)
    - Harcourt, Brace, 1935 (Folder 145)
    - Holt, Rinehart, and Winston, 1959-1965 (Folder 146)
    - Humanities Press -- Philosophical Studies, 1965, 1970 (Folder 147)
    - John Wiley & Sons, 1954, 1961 (Folder 148)
    - Julius Springer, 1929 (Folder 149)
    - Knopf/Random House, 1966-1967, 1971 (Folder 150)
    - MacMillanCorrespondence with Publishers -- MacMillan, 1954 (Folder 151)
    - MacMillan Co. (Crowell Collier & MacMillan) -- Encyclopedia of Philosophy, 1963-1967 (Folder 152)
    - Open Court -- Library of LIving Philosophers, 1961 (Folder 153)
    - Philosopher's Index (Folder 154)
    - Prentice-Hall, 1960-1965 (Folder 155)
    - Princeton University Press, 1969 (Folder 156)
    - Reidel, 1971 (Folder 157)
    - Routledge & Kegan Paul -- Current Issues in Philosophy of Science, 1960 (Folder 158)
    - Springer-Verlag, 1960 (Folder 159)
    - Springer-Verlag -- LIbrary of Exact Philosphy, 1968-1970 (Folder 160)
    - Thomas Nelson & Sons, 1963 (Folder 161)
    - University of Chicago Press, 1961 (Folder 162)
    - University of Chicago Press -- Foundations of Science Series & Index and Bibliography to the IEUS, 1965-1972 (Folder 163)
    - University of Minnesota Press, 1953-1971 (Folder 164)
    - University of North Carolina Press, 1967 (Folder 165)
    - Wayne State University Press, 1966 (Folder 166)
    - William and Wilkins, 1967 (Folder 167)
    - Audiorecording I., 1961 (Folder 168)
    - Audiorecording II., 1968 (Folder 169)
    - Audiorecording III. (Folder 170)
    - Protocol (Folder 171)
    - Protocol -- Los Angeles, 1955 (Folder 172)
    - Protocol -- Princeton, 1954 (Folder 173)
- Writings by Feigl, 1927-1971; IV.
  This series is divided into "Lectures and Notes" and "Papers" by Feigl. Feigls lectures and notes comprise a few lecture outlines but mostly research notes on a wide range of scientific topics from Darwin, Copernnicus, Marx, and Freud to discussions of free will and the philosophy of psychology. The subseries "Papers" contains some book reviews by Feigl and of his work but for the most part represents an extensive compilation of Feigls manuscript drafts, some accompanied by the final published offprint.
  - Lectures and Notes, 1931-1970; 1.
    - Lectures, 1947-1956 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Lecture Announcements, 1936-1970 (Folder 2)
    - Notes I (Folder 3)
    - Notes II, 1931-1959 (Folder 4)
    - Notes III, 1942-1962 (Reel 7, Folder 5)
    - Notes IV, 1956 (Folder 6)
    - Notes V, 1950-1967 (Folder 7)
    - Notes VI, 1954, 1964 (Folder 8)
    - Notes VII, 1933-1934, 1968 (Folder 9)
    - Notes VIII, 1969 (Folder 10)
    - Notes IX, 1941, 1943 (Folder 11)
    - Notes X (Folder 12)
    - Notes XI, 1941-1953 (Folder 13)
    - Notes XII, 1956 (Folder 14)
    - Notes XIII (Folder 15)
    - Notes XIV, 1953 (Folder 16)
    - Notes XV, 1955, 1963-1966 (Folder 17)
    - Notes XVI, 1941, 1944-1945 (Folder 18)
    - Notes XVII, 1937, 1946 (Folder 19)
    - Notes (Drawings) (Folder 20)
    - Notes (Miscellaneous), 1933-1970 (Folder 21)
  - Papers by Herbert Feigl, 1927-1971; 2.
    - Book Reviews (authored by Feigl), 1934-1971 (Folder 22)
    - Book Reviews (of Feigl's works), 1943-1956 (Folder 23)
    - Reviews of Minnesota Studies I, 1956-1958 (Folder 24)
    - Review of Minnesota Studies II, 1958-1961 (Folder 25)
    - "Abschrift: Beurteilun[n]g der Dissertation des cand. phil. Herbert Feigl: "Zufall und Gestz", 1927 (Folder 26)
    - "Aims of Education for Our Age of Science", 1955 (Folder 27)
    - "The Aldrich vs. Feigl Discussion", 1935 (Folder 28)
    - "Analogical Inference of Other Minds", 1954 (Folder 29)
    - "An Anthology of Logical Positivism" (Folder 30)
    - "Art, Moral Faith and the Scientific Outlook" (Folder 31)
    - "At the Limits of Meaning" (Folder 32)
    - "Axiological Truth?" (Folder 33)
    - "Beyond Peaceful Coexistence" (Folder 34)
    - "A Bibliographical Resume of Some American Contributions to the Philosophy of Science" (Folder 35)
    - "Bibliography and Index", 1969 (Folder 36)
    - "Carnap, Rudolf, 1891-1970" (Folder 37)
    - "Causality, Chance and Scientific Explanation", 1969 (Folder 38)
    - "Comments on Farrell's 'The Limits of Experiemental Psychology'", 1955 (Folder 39)
    - "The Compleat [sic] Autocerebroscopist", 1954 (Folder 40)
    - "Confirmability and Confirmation", 1951 (Folder 41)
    - "Critique of Dialectical Materialism" (Folder 42)
    - "Critique of Inuition According to Scientific Empiricism", 1958 (Folder 43)
    - "Crucial Issues of Mind-Body Monism", 1966 (Folder 44)
    - "De Principiis non Disputandum", 1933-1934 (Reel 8, Folder 45)
    - "The Determinism-Freedom and Body-Mind Problems", 1971 (Folder 46)
    - "A Dialogue Concerning Empiricism vs. Theology", 1955 (Folder 47)
    - "The Difference Between Knowledge and Valuation", 1950 (Folder 48)
    - "The Difference Between Robots and Human Beings", 1954 (Folder 49)
    - "A Discussion of Some Perplexities Regarding the 'Mental' and the 'Physical'" (Folder 50)
    - "Discussion Remarks", 1970 (Folder 51)
    - "The Distinction Between Analytic and Synthetic Statements as the Cornerstone of Logical Empiricism", 1966 (Folder 52)
    - "Empirical Realism" (Folder 53)
    - "Empiricism at Bay?", 1971 (Folder 54)
    - "Existential Hypotheses", 1950 (Folder 55)
    - "Explication of 'Explanation", 1954 (Folder 56)
    - "An Explicit Statement of Reductionism", 1954 (Folder 57)
    - "A Few Points on 'Clouds and Clocks' and 'Body-Mind'" (Folder 58)
    - "First Preliminary Response to Carnap and Mehlberg on my 'Puzzle", 1956 (Folder 59)
    - "From Logical Positivism to Hypercritical Realism", 1963 (Folder 60)
    - "Functionalism, Psychological Theory, and the Uniting Sciences", 1955 (Folder 61)
    - "Gas Molecules as Theoretical Constructs", 1955 (Folder 62)
    - "Gemeinsame Besprechung beider Arbeitsgemeinschaften", 1964 (Folder 63)
    - "Das Hypothetisch-Konstruktive Denken", 1956 (Folder 64)
    - "Ideal Aims of Humanity", 1965 (Folder 65)
    - "Identity vs. Epiphenomenalism", 1954 (Folder 66)
    - "Indeterminism and Contemporary Science" (Folder 67)
    - "Is Science Relevant to Theology?" (Folder 68)
    - "Is There Knowledge by Intuition?", 1958 (Folder 69)
    - "Levels of Scientific Inquiry", 1956 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - "Liberal Education Content in Science Education", 1961 (Folder 2)
    - "Logical Analysis of the Psycho-Physical Problem", 1934 (Folder 3)
    - "The Logical Character of the Principle of Induction", 1932, 1934 (Folder 4)
    - "Logical Empiricism", 1943 (Folder 5)
    - "Logical Empiricism and the Unity of Science Movement", 1970 (Folder 6)
    - "Logical Empiricism after 25 Years", 1953 (Folder 7)
    - "The Logical Empiricists in the United States" (Folder 8)
    - "Logical Positivism after 35 Years", 1963-1964, 1966 (Folder 9)
    - "Logical Truth and the World", 1962 (Folder 10)
    - "Matter Still Largely Material", 1962 (Folder 11)
    - "Meaning and Reference", 1963 (Folder 12)
    - "The Meaning of Freedom", 1942 (Folder 13)
    - "The Meaning of Value Judgements" (Folder 14)
    - "The 'Mental' and the 'Physical'" (Folder 15)
    - "Miller, Dickinson S." (Folder 16)
    - "The Mind-Body Problem in the Development of Logical Empiricism" (Folder 17)
    - "Models of Man", 1965 (Folder 18)
    - "Modernized Theology and the Scientific Outlook", 1963 (Folder 19)
    - "Naturalisimo e Umanesimo" (Folder 20)
    - "A New Puzzle for Epiphenominalism", 1956 (Folder 21)
    - "[Newton and Einstein], 1921-1949 (Folder 22)
    - "A Note on Justification and Reconstruction", 1958 (Folder 23)
    - "On the Nature of Value Judgements" (Folder 24)
    - "On the Vindication of Induction", 1961 (Folder 25)
    - "Operationism and Scientific Method", 1945 (Reel 9, Folder 26)
    - "The Origin and Spirit of Logical Positivism", 1966, 1969 (Folder 27)
    - "The 'Orthodox' View of Theories" (Folder 28)
    - "Other Minds and the Egocentric Predicament", 1958 (Folder 29)
    - "The Outlook of Scientific Humanism", 1959, 1966 (Folder 30)
    - "Philosophical Embarrassments of Psychology", 1958-1959, 1962 (Folder 31)
    - "Philosophical Interpretations of Contemporary Psychology" (Folder 32)
    - "Philosophical Tangents of Science", 1959, 1961 (Folder 33)
    - "Philosophy as Clarification", 1950 (Folder 34)
    - "Philosophy for Our Age of Science" (Folder 35)
    - "The Philosophy of Mysticism" (Folder 36)
    - "The Philosophy of Science of Logical Empiricism", 1954 (Folder 37)
    - "Physicalism as the Foundations of Psychology" (Folder 38)
    - "Physicalism as I See It", 1954 (Folder 39)
    - "Physicalism, Unity of Science and the Foundations of Psychology", 1963 (Folder 40)
    - "Positivism and Logical Empiricism" (Folder 41)
    - "Positivism -- Not Negativism", 1935 (Folder 42)
    - "Postscript After Ten Years", 1967 (Folder 43)
    - "Postscript on 'Martians' and 'Captive Minds'" (Folder 44)
    - "The Power of Positivistic Thinking", 1963 (Folder 45)
    - "Principles and Problems of Theory Construction in Psychology", 1951 (Folder 46)
    - "Proposed Plan of Work", 1939, 1941 (Folder 47)
    - "The Psychology of Mysticism" (Folder 48)
    - "Realistic Empiricism versus Conventionalistic Pragmatism" (Folder 49)
    - "Recent American Philosophy of Science" (Folder 50)
    - "Reduction of Psychology to Neurophysiology?" (Folder 51)
    - "Russell and Schlick" (Folder 52)
    - "Schlick, Moritz" (Folder 53)
    - "Science and Philosophy", 1965 (Folder 54)
    - "Science as an Instrument to Foretell and to Shape the Future", 1961 (Folder 55)
    - "Scientific Method Without Metaphysical Presuppositions", 1951, 1954 (Folder 56)
    - "The Scientific Outlook in Philosophy and the Issues of Education", 1947 (Folder 57)
    - "The Scientific Outlook: Naturalism and Humanism", 1949 (Folder 58)
    - "Scienza e Teologia" (Folder 59)
    - "Sense and Nonsense in Scientific Realism" (Folder 60)